Jascha Ephraim

3827 Clarke St Oakland, CA 94609 202-470-6098

jaschaephraim@gmail.com https://github.com/jaschaephraim http://jaschaephraim.com

SUMMARY

I am currently contracted as the sole engineer for the Gems Ethereum token and platform, and have been a freelance developer since 2005. I have professional experience with a variety of frontend, backend, and blockchain technologies, and enjoy adapting quickly to new ones.

My work is informed by multiple aptitudes and life experiences, including musical composition and performance, multimedia production, writing and editing, and Buddhist chaplaincy.

PROFICIENCIES

- · Blockchain: Solidity, Truffle Framework, MetaMask
- · Backend: Go, Node.js, Python, PHP, Ruby, MySQL, Postgres, MongoDB, Neo4J
- Frontend: JavaScript/ES6, CoffeeScript, Webpack, React, Redux, CSS3, HTML5
- Devops: Sysadmin, AWS, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, Docker
- Scientific applications: Java, Matlab, R, E-Prime

NOTABLE PROJECTS

- Gems Ethereum token and microtask platform.
- <u>Emergency Market Mapping and Analysis Tool</u> developed for the International Rescue Committee and USAID. Browser-based, offline graphical mapping tool utilizing ES6, React, Redux, Immutable.js, Cytoscape.js, Webpack.
- <u>Bayesian decision network modeler and evaluator</u> written in Java, implementing both absolute probability calculation and estimation via Gibbs sampling.
- Static website generator and development environment written in Node.js.
- · LiveReload server for Go.
- Article on Elementary Neural Networks with TensorFlow: Training Perceptrons to Do Boolean Logic.

RELEVANT EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

2018-present Software Engineer

Gems

Designed, developed, and deployed Solidity contracts and full-stack web application for the Gems ICO and microtask platform. Involved interactions with the Ethereum blockchain via MetaMask in the browser and dedicated Node.js server instances on the backend. Using Node.js, Go, React/Redux, Google Cloud, Kubernetes, Truffle Framework.

2017 Software Engineer

Gifs.com

Full-stack development and devops for browser-based image/video editor, including implementation of server-side video processing. Using Node.js, Go, React/Redux, Google Cloud, Kubernetes.

2016 Software Engineer

Cargomatic

Full-stack development—specializing in backend—of scalable shipping platform, including web and mobile clients, real-time location tracking, billing, operations administration, exception ticketing and resolution. Built using Node.js, Go, React, AWS.

2005–2015 Freelance Web Developer

Provided web design and development services, adapting open-source content management systems and creating custom frameworks.

2010–2011 Research Assistant

Laboratory of Professor Michael Spivey, Ph.D.

University of California, Merced

Assisted in design and implementation of behavioral experiments, ran subjects, maintained detailed records. Experiments involved mouse tracking, eye tracking, timed visual search.

Research Programmer

Laboratory of Professor Evan Heit, Ph.D.

University of California, Merced

Programmed experiments according to specifications using Java and E-Prime. Studies addressed judgements involving deduction, induction, and varying reliability of information sources.

Web Developer/Graphic Designer/Proofreader

Laboratory of Professor Qinghua Guo, Ph.D.

University of California, Merced

Designed lab and departmental websites, design and layout of print materials, proofreading of scientific journal submissions. Articles addressed spatial analysis of environmental LIDAR data.

EDUCATION

2012–2015	University of the West Rosemead, CA M.Div., Buddhist Chaplaincy
2010–2011	University of California Merced, CA B.S., Cognitive Science High Honors, Dean's List, Chancellor's List
2009–2010	City College of San Francisco San Francisco, CA
2003–2004	University of North Carolina Asheville, NC
2000-2003	Warren Wilson College Swannanoa, NC